<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on berkeley.notes</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Home on berkeley.notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 1: Intro, Measurement, Estimating</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/1/</guid><description>Pretty rudimentary stuff&amp;hellip;
Come back and add the basic dimensional analysis and etc that seems vaguely important</description></item><item><title>Week 1</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/ugba135/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/ugba135/1/</guid><description>Title: : Intro to Personal Financial Management + Who Are the Millionares? + Financial Planning in a World of Credit and Debt Reading: Chapters 1, 2, and 3 Videos
Chapter 1: Introduction # What is our definition of a millionaire? Those financially indpendent to take care of themselves If the biggest financial problem is no longer retirement, what is it? Lonegivity is the biggesst problem, living beyond what you planned for Do most people pay more in Social Security and Medicare than federal income taxes?</description></item><item><title>Chapter 2: Describing Motion: Kinematics in 1D</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/2/</guid><description>Mechanics: study of motion of objects, and the related concepts of forec and engergy 1. Kinematics: description of how objects move 2. Dynamics: deals with force and why objects move as they do
translational motion is when objects move without rotation (a point particle can only undergo translational motion) 2.1: Reference Frames and Displacement # measurements are taken from a certain viewpoint → called a reference frame in physics</description></item><item><title>Complexity and Algoritmic Analysis</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/cs61b/complexity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/cs61b/complexity/</guid><description>https://joshhug.gitbooks.io/hug61b/content/chap8/chap82.html
Considerations # in regards to an engineer, there are some crucial things to consider -&amp;gt; operational cost, the development costs, the maintenacne costs, and costs of failure is the program fast enough (purpose + input data factor in) the space - memory, disk space - dephends on input data as well and, scale (as input gets big) execution cost, that is, the cost of execution in terms of time and space/memory, is referred to as time complexity and space complexity</description></item><item><title>Week 2</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/ugba135/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/ugba135/2/</guid><description>Title : Financial Planning in a World of Credit and Debt (continued) + Contracts + Understanding Social Security, Medicare and You Reading: Chapters 4,5, and 6 Videos
Chapter 4: Credit Reports and Credit Scores # What is the difference between a credit report and a credit score? Credit report is an individual financial report card that describes if the subject of the report has been making credit card and loan payments on time (includes a great deal of personal information), while a credit score is a culmination of the info on your credit report Who are the 3 major credit reporting agencies?</description></item><item><title>Chapter 3: Kinematics in Two or Three Dimensions; Vectors</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/3/</guid><description>3.1: Vectors and Scalars # vectors have magnitude and direction those without magnitude (but with direction) are called scalar quantities 3.2: Addition of Vectors - Graphical Methods # when considering displacement on a line, addition (and subtractino) is easy
displacement when someone walks 10 km east, then walks 5 km (i.e a quantity with both value and direction), change in position = ?</description></item><item><title>Packages and Access</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/cs61b/packages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/cs61b/packages/</guid><description>Non netsted classes or interfacnes may be public or package private
Classes without a modifier are package private (only accesible within the same package)
Members of a class (attriubes/fields/instance variables, methods, constructors, nested types) can be any of the four access levels
Access is based on static not dynamic types -&amp;gt; class not object
Only override a method with one that is at least as permissive</description></item><item><title>Week 3</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/ugba135/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/ugba135/3/</guid><description>Title : Government Revenues and Expenses Reading: Chapter 7 Videos
Assingment #2
#</description></item><item><title>Chapter 4: Dynamics: Newton's Laws of Motion</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/4/</guid><description>4.1: Force # Force, as it is largely known, is a push or pull on an object Force is needed to accelerate an object Force is a vector 4.2: Newton&amp;rsquo;s First Law of Motion # Galileo imagined an idealealized world → one without friction With this in mind, Galileo realized that without force on a moving object, it will continue to move with constant speed in a straight line This idea leads into Newton&amp;rsquo;s 1st Law Every object continues in its state of rest, or of uniform velocity in a staight line, as long as no net force acts on it.</description></item><item><title>Integers</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/cs61b/integer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/cs61b/integer/</guid><description>Integers Types and Literals # the range of values for signed types -2^N .. 2^N - 1 (there is 1 less value for posivite values to account for 0) the range of values for unsigned types 0 .. 2^N - 1
(N is the number of bits)
how do we handle &amp;lsquo;overflow&amp;rsquo;, numbers that are so large they are outside the range, java employs modular arithmetic (&amp;lsquo;wrapping around&amp;rsquo;)</description></item><item><title>Project 2: Ataax</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/cs61b/project2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/cs61b/project2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Linux : Processes</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/processes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/processes/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>