<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on berkeley.notes</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Home on berkeley.notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 1: Intro, Measurement, Estimating</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/1/</guid><description>Pretty rudimentary stuff&amp;hellip;
Come back and add the basic dimensional analysis and etc that seems vaguely important</description></item><item><title>Week 1: Intro to Personal Financial Management + Who Are the Millionares? + Financial Planning in a World of Credit and Debt</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/ugba135/1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/ugba135/1/</guid><description>Reading: Chapters 1, 2, and 3 Videos
Chapter 1: Introduction # What is our definition of a millionaire? Those financially indpendent to take care of themselves If the biggest financial problem is no longer retirement, what is it? Lonegivity is the biggesst problem, living beyond what you planned for Do most people pay more in Social Security and Medicare than federal income taxes? Most people pay more in SS and Medicare taxes than federal income taxes What is the difference between being rich and being wealthy?</description></item><item><title>Chapter 2: Describing Motion: Kinematics in 1D</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/2/</guid><description>Mechanics: study of motion of objects, and the related concepts of forec and engergy 1. Kinematics: description of how objects move 2. Dynamics: deals with force and why objects move as they do
translational motion is when objects move without rotation (a point particle can only undergo translational motion) 2.1: Reference Frames and Displacement # measurements are taken from a certain viewpoint → called a reference frame in physics</description></item><item><title>Week 2: Financial Planning in a World of Credit and Debt (continued) + Contracts + Understanding Social Security, Medicare and You</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/ugba135/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/ugba135/2/</guid><description>Reading: Chapters 4,5, and 6 Videos
Chapter 4: Credit Reports and Credit Scores # What is the difference between a credit report and a credit score? Credit report is an individual financial report card that describes if the subject of the report has been making credit card and loan payments on time (includes a great deal of personal information), while a credit score is a culmination of the info on your credit report Who are the 3 major credit reporting agencies?</description></item><item><title>Chapter 3: Kinematics in Two or Three Dimensions; Vectors</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/physics7a/3/</guid><description>3.1: Vectors and Scalars # vectors have magnitude and direction those without magnitude (but with direction) are called scalar quantities 3.2: Addition of Vectors - Graphical Methods # when considering displacement on a line, addition (and subtractino) is easy
displacement when someone walks 10 km east, then walks 5 km (i.e a quantity with both value and direction), change in position = ?</description></item><item><title>Project 0</title><link>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/cs61b/projcect0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rohan-mantena.github.io/notes/cs61b/projcect0/</guid><description>project-home-page summary of instructions # setup: the puzzle # : the actual puzzle is a grid of empty square cells (the board) and a set of a number of pieces that are in the form of a configuration of those sqaure cell blocks (one's hand) - after each piece is placed, any cells that have been filled are cleared - after all the pieces inone&amp;rsquo;s hand are placed, it is refilled with the same number of pieces as before - play continues until none of the pieces in the hand can fit anywhere on the board</description></item></channel></rss>